Guide to the Alexander Hamilton Papers Publication Project records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Alexander Hamilton Papers Publication Project Records,
[ca. 1700]-1981
Hamilton, Alexander, 1757-1804.
ca. 96,000 items, (304 boxes, 282 microfilm reels, 32 card file drawers)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078858
Biographical Note
Harold C. Syrett (1913- ) was the editor for this project (M.A., 1938; Ph.D., 1944).
Scope and Content
Correspondence, typescripts, photocopies, microfilms, card files, and notes of the Alexander Hamilton Papers Publication Project, 1955-1981. The correspondence files of the editor, Harold C. Syrett, and his staff concerning the operations, activities, gathering of data, photocopies, and microfilm reproductions of letters, manuscripts, and documents by, to, and about Alexander Hamilton and selected and edited for publication by Columbia University Press as The Papers of Alexander Hamilton (New York, 1961-1970). Also, the corrected typescript copies of texts to be published, photocopies of letters, manuscripts, and documents by, to, and about Alexander Hamilton; microfilms of manuscript materials in a variety of repositories; and photocopies of newspaper articles relating to Hamilton.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Special Files
Series III: Chronology
Series IV: Typescriopt Files
Series V: Book Reviews of the Published Volumes
Series VI: Photocopies of Letters, Manuscripts and Documents
Series VII: Microfilms
Series VIII. Card File Indexes
Subjects
Columbia University.--Press.; Syrett, Harold Coffin, 1913-; United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.; United States--History--1783-1815.; Scholarly publishing.; Statesmen.; Lawyers.
Access Restrictions
This collection has no restrictions.
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
Acquisition
1981 M-81 Columbia University Press Gift
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries I.1: Office Correspondence
    - A-Bos (Box 1)
    - Bow-Columbia Univ. Press (A-M) (Box 2)
    - Columbia Univ. Press (P-W)-Congress, Library of (Box 3)
    - Conn-Fic (Box 4)
    - Fis-Hay (Box 5)
    - Hen-Knowlton I (Box 6)
    - Knowlton II-Mars (Box 7)
    - Mary-Nas (Box 8)
    - National Archives (A-Hamer/Holmes) (Box 9)
    - National Archives (Hamilton-M)-Newsweek (Box 10)
    - New York-Pell (Box 11)
    - Penn-Rus (Box 12)
    - Rut-Urs (Box 13)
    - Val-You and Letters of Inquiry (A-F) (Box 14)
    - Letters of Inquiry (G-W) (Box 15)
  - Subseries I.2: Correspondence for Documents
    - A-Bar (Box 16)
    - Bat-Brown (Box 17)
    - Bru-Chap (Box 18)
    - Char-Day (Box 19)
    - Dea-Ell (Box 20)
    - Elm-Fra (Box 21)
    - Fre-Hay (Box 22)
    - He-Ill (Box 23)
    - In-Kro (Box 24)
    - Ku-McCormick (Box 25)
    - McGhee-Mis (Box 26)
    - Mit-New Mexico (Box 27)
    - New Milford-O (Box 28)
    - P-Q (Box 29)
    - R-Sag (Box 30)
    - Saint-Sea (Box 31)
    - Sed-Sta (Box 32)
    - Ste-U (Box 33)
    - V-Wic (Box 34)
    - Wil-Z (Box 35)
- Series II: Special Files
  - A-Cor (Box 36)
  - Cox-Ham (Box 37)
  - Hol-McHenry (Box 38)
  - McHenry (1798-1800)-Morris (Box 39)
  - N (Box 40)
  - P-W (Box 41)
- Series III: Chronology
  - Chronology (1793-1804) (Box 42)
- Series IV: Typescriopt Files
  For publications
  - Subseries IV.1: Addenda, Errata, Sources
    - Addenda (Box 43)
    - Errata (Vols. I-XI, XIV-XXV) (Box 43)
    - Errata, Addenda, & Second Sources (Vols. I-XXV) (Box 43)
    - Second Sources (1769-1790) (Box 44)
  - Subseries IV.2: Appendix, 1799-1800
    - 14 May-31 Oct 1799 (Box 45)
    - 1 Nov 1799-31 Jan 1800 (Box 46)
    - 1 Feb-24 June 1800 (Box 47)
  - Subseries IV.3: Retypes, 1794-1804
    - Jan 1794-10 Mar 1794 (Box 48)
    - 11 Mar 1794-May 1794 (Box 49)
    - June 1794-Aug 1794 (Box 50)
    - Sept 1794-Dec 1794 (Box 51)
    - Jan-Feb 1795 (Box 52)
    - March-July 1795 (Box 53)
    - Aug-Dec 1795 (Box 54)
    - Jan-15 June 1796 (Box 55)
    - 16 June-Dec 1796 (Box 56)
    - Jan-Dec 1797 (Box 57)
    - Jan-July 1798 (Box 58)
    - Aug-Dec 1798 (Box 59)
    - Jan-April 1799 (Box 60)
    - May-Aug 1799 (Box 61)
    - Sept-Dec 1799 (Box 62)
    - Jan-March 1800 (Box 63)
    - April-4 July 1800 (Box 64)
    - 5 July-Aug 1800 (Box 65)
    - Sept-Dec 1800 (Box 66)
    - Jan-Dec 1801 (Box 67)
    - Jan-Dec 1802 (Box 68)
    - Jan-Dec 1803 (Box 69)
    - Jan-Dec 1804 (Box 70)
  - Subseries IV.4: Retypes, A-Z
    - A-Bar (Box 71)
    - Boy-D (Box 72)
    - E-F (Box 73)
    - Ham-Int (Box 74)
    - Ire-M (Box 75)
    - N-Rey (Box 76)
    - Ric-Sec (Box 77)
    - Sed-W (Box 78)
    - Volumes 1-25 (Box 79)
    - Supplementary Volumes I-III (Box 80)
    - Supplementary Volumes IV-V (Box 81)
    - Appendix Retypes, July 1798-15 July 1799 (Box 82)
    - Appendix Retypes, 16 June-19 Aug 1799 (Box 83)
    - Appendix Retypes, 20 Aug-Sept 1799 (Box 84)
- Series V: Book Reviews of the Published Volumes
  - Book Reviews (Box 85)
- Series VI: Photocopies of Letters, Manuscripts and Documents
  - Subseries VI.1: Main Files
    - 19 Feb 1768-1773 (Box 86)
    - 1774-5 April 1777 (Box 87)
    - 8 April 1777-29 Aug 1777 (Box 88)
    - 1 Sept 1777-30 Oct 1777 (Box 89)
    - 2 Nov 1777-18 June 1778 (Box 90)
    - 25 June 1778-24 Dec 1778 (Box 91)
    - 8 Jan 1779-8 Aug 1779 (Box 92)
    - 10 Aug 1779-15 Nov 1779 (Box 93)
    - 1 Dec 1779-31 May 1780 (Box 94)
    - 7 June 1780-8 Oct 1780 (Box 95)
    - 10 Oct 1780-19 Feb 1781 (Box 96)
    - 21 Feb-16 Sept 1781 (Box 97)
    - 12 Oct 1781-13 Aug 1782 (Box 98)
    - 15 Aug 1782-13 Jan 1783 (Box 99)
    - 22 Jan 1783-22 April 1783 (Box 100)
    - 23 April-July 1783 (Box 101)
    - 5 Aug 1783-30 Aug 1784 (Box 102)
    - Sept 1784-July 1786 (Box 103)
    - 2 Aug 1786-2 Feb 1787 (Box 104)
    - 1 March 1787-19 June 1787 (Box 105)
    - 21 June 1787-30 Nov 1787 (Box 106)
    - Dec 1787-13 June 1788 (Box 107)
    - 17 June 1788 (Box 108)
    - 19 June 1788-26 Aug 1788 (Box 109)
    - 29 Aug 1788-3 March 1789 (Box 110)
    - 4 March 1789-19 Sept 1789 (Box 111)
    - 20 Sept 1789-10 Oct 1789 (Box 112)
    - 11 Oct 1789-7 Nov 1789 (Box 113)
    - 8 Nov 1789-30 Nov 1789 (Box 114)
    - Dec 1789 (Box 115)
    - Jan 1790 (Box 116)
    - Feb-12 March 1790 (Box 117)
    - 13 March-22 April 1790 (Box 118)
    - 26 April-7 June 1790 (Box 119)
    - 8 June-25 July 1790 (Box 120)
    - 26 July-27 Aug 1790 (Box 121)
    - 28 Aug-24 Sept 1790 (Box 122)
    - 25 Sept-18 Oct 1790 (Box 123)
    - 19 Oct-30 Nov 1790 (Box 124)
    - 1 Dec-16 Dec 1790 (Box 125)
    - 17 Dec 1790-10 Jan 1791 (Box 126)
    - 11 Jan-31 Jan 1791 (Box 127)
    - 1 Feb-22 Feb 1791 (Box 128)
    - 23 Feb-28 Feb 1791 (Box 129)
    - March 1791 (Box 130)
    - 1 April-19 April 1791 (Box 131)
    - 20 April-24 May 1791 (Box 132)
    - 25 May-14 June 1791 (Box 133)
    - 15 June-8 July 1791 (Box 134)
    - 9 July-10 Aug 1791 (Box 135)
    - 11 Aug-29 Aug 1791 (Box 136)
    - 30 Aug-16 Sept 1791 (Box 137)
    - 17 Sept-5 Oct 1791 (Box 138)
    - 6 Oct-26 Oct 1791 (Box 139)
    - 27 Oct-17 Nov 1791 (Box 140)
    - 18 Nov-3 Dec 1791 (Box 141)
    - 5 Dec 1791 (Box 142)
    - 6 Dec-31 Dec 1791 (Box 143)
    - 1 Jan-23 Jan 1792 (Box 144)
    - 24 Jan-29 Feb 1792 (Box 145)
    - 1 March-19 March 1792 (Box 146)
    - 20 March-10 April 1792 (Box 147)
    - 11 April-7 May 1792 (Box 148)
    - 8 May-4 June 1792 (Box 149)
    - 5 June-25 June 1792 (Box 150)
    - 26 June-16 July 1792 (Box 151)
    - 17 July-3 Aug 1792 (Box 152)
    - 4 Aug-20 Aug 1792 (Box 153)
    - 21 Aug-8 Sept-1792 (Box 154)
    - 9 Sept-25 Sept-1792 (Box 155)
    - 26 Sept-17 Oct 1792 (Box 156)
    - 18 Oct-9 Nov 1792 (Box 157)
    - 10 Nov-23 Nov 1792 (Box 158)
    - 24 Nov-18 Dec 1792 (Box 159)
    - 19 Dec 1792-10 Jan 1793 (Box 160)
    - 11 Jan-13 Feb 1793 (Box 161)
    - 14 Feb-2 March 1793 (Box 162)
    - 4 March-3 April 1793 (Box 163)
    - 4 April-30 April 1793 (Box 164)
    - 1 May-16 May 1793 (Box 165)
    - 17 May-15 June 1793 (Box 166)
    - 16 June-13 July 1793 (Box 167)
    - 15 July-4 Aug 1793 (Box 168)
    - 5 Aug-26 Aug 1793 (Box 169)
    - 27 Aug-6 Nov 1793 (Box 170)
    - 7 Nov-16 Dec 1793 (Box 171)
    - 17 Dec 1793-9 Jan 1794 (Box 172)
    - 10 Jan-10 Feb 1794 (Box 173)
    - 11 Feb-17 March 1794 (Box 174)
    - 18 March-5 April 1794 (Box 175)
    - 7 April-26 April 1794 (Box 176)
    - 27 April-26 May 1794 (Box 177)
    - 27 May-19 June 1794 (Box 178)
    - 20 June-8 July 1794 (Box 179)
    - 9 July-5 Aug 1794 (Box 180)
    - 6 Aug-25 Aug 1794 (Box 181)
    - 26 Aug-17 Sept 1794 (Box 182)
    - 18 Sept-21 Oct 1794 (Box 183)
    - 22 Oct-8 Dec 1794 (Box 184)
    - 9 Dec 1794-5 Jan 1795 (Box 185)
    - 6 Jan-21 Jan 1795 (Box 186)
    - 22 Jan-17 Feb 1795 (Box 187)
    - 18 Feb-9 July 1795 (Box 188)
    - 10 July-11 Aug 1795 (Box 189)
    - 12 Aug-22 Sept 1795 (Box 190)
    - 26 Sept-18 Nov 1795 (Box 191)
    - 19 Nov-31 Dec 1795 (Box 192)
    - 1 Jan-22 April 1796 (Box 193)
    - 23 April-14 July 1796 (Box 194)
    - 15 July-29 Oct 1796 (Box 195)
    - Nov 1796-Jan 1797 (Box 196)
    - 4 Feb-15 April 1797 (Box 197)
    - 16 April-17 July 1797 (Box 198)
    - 18 July-Dec 1797 (Box 199)
    - 1 Jan-25 March 1798 (Box 200)
    - 27 March-5 June 1798 (Box 201)
    - 6 June-July 1798 (Box 202)
    - 1 Aug-5 Sept 1798 (Box 203)
    - 6 Sept-17 Nov 1798 (Box 204)
    - 19 Nov-Dec 1798 (Box 205)
    - Jan 1799-6 Feb 1799 (Box 206)
    - 7 Feb-4 March 1799 (Box 207)
    - 5 March-19 March 1799 (Box 208)
    - 20 March-2 April 1799 (Box 209)
    - 3 April-14 April 1799 (Box 210)
    - 15 April-25 April 1799 (Box 211)
    - 26 April-3 May 1799 (Box 212)
    - 4 May-17 May 1799 (Box 213)
    - 18 May-25 May 1799 (Box 214)
    - 26 May-5 June 1799 (Box 215)
    - 6 June-15 June 1799 (Box 216)
    - 16 June-25 June 1799 (Box 217)
    - 26 June-5 July 1799 (Box 218)
    - 6 July-18 July 1799 (Box 219)
    - 19 July-31 July 1799 (Box 220)
    - 1 Aug-16 Aug 1799 (Box 221)
    - 17 Aug-26 Aug 1799 (Box 222)
    - 27 Aug-5 Sept 1799 (Box 223)
    - 6 Sept-13 Sept 1799 (Box 224)
    - 14 Sept-19 Sept 1799 (Box 225)
    - 20 Sept-26 Sept 1799 (Box 226)
    - 27 Sept-3 Oct 1799 (Box 227)
    - 4 Oct-11 Oct 1799 (Box 228)
    - 12 Oct-20 Oct 1799 (Box 229)
    - 21 Oct-25 Oct 1799 (Box 230)
    - 26 Oct-31 Oct 1799 (Box 231)
    - 1 Nov-8 Nov 1799 (Box 232)
    - 9 Nov-15 Nov 1799 (Box 233)
    - 16 Nov-24 Nov 1799 (Box 234)
    - 25 Nov-5 Dec 1799 (Box 235)
    - 6 Dec-19 Dec 1799 (Box 236)
    - 20 Dec 1799-2 Jan 1800 (Box 237)
    - 3 Jan-13 Jan 1800 (Box 238)
    - 14 Jan-8 Feb 1800 (Box 239)
    - 10 Feb-24 Feb 1800 (Box 240)
    - 25 Feb-4 March 1800 (Box 241)
    - 5 March-12 March 1800 (Box 242)
    - 13 March-24 March 1800 (Box 243)
    - 25 March-2 April 1800 (Box 244)
    - 3 April-20 April 1800 (Box 245)
    - 21 April-3 May 1800 (Box 246)
    - 4 May-13 May 1800 (Box 247)
    - 14 May-24 May 1800 (Box 248)
    - 26 May-24 June 1800 (Box 249)
    - 25 June-24 Aug 1800 (Box 250)
    - 25 Aug-18 Nov 1800 (Box 251)
    - 19 Nov 1800-25 Feb 1801 (Box 252)
    - March-Dec 1801 (Box 253)
    - 2 Jan-10 Aug 1802 (Box 254)
    - 13 Aug 1802-June 1803 (Box 255)
    - July 1803-March 1804 (Box 256)
    - 10 April-10 July 1804 (Box 257)
    - 11 July 1804-15 March 1806 (Box 258)
    - No Date (A-W) (Box 259)
  - Subseries VI.2: Neither/Nor File
    - 1725-1783 (Box 260)
    - 1784-1789 (Box 261)
    - Jan-Dec 1790 (Box 262)
    - Jan-8 Sept 1791 (Box 263)
    - 10 Sept 1791-March 1792 (Box 264)
    - April-Oct 1792 (Box 265)
    - Nov 1792-16 March 1793 (Box 266)
    - 18 March-Nov 1793 (Box 267)
    - Dec 1793-14 May 1794 (Box 268)
    - 15 May-13 Nov 1794 (Box 269)
    - 14 Nov 1794-Feb 1795 (Box 270)
    - March 1795-Dec 1796 (Box 271)
    - Jan 1797-21 Aug 1798 (Box 272)
    - 22 Aug 1798-26 Feb 1799 (Box 273)
    - 27 Feb-June 1799 (Box 274)
    - July 1799-March 1800 (Box 275)
    - April 1800-Dec 1800 (Box 276)
    - Jan 1801 (Box 277)
    - 2 Feb 1801-21 April 1802 (Box 278)
    - May 1802-1804 (Box 279)
    - 1805-1822 (Box 280)
    - 1823-1837 (Box 281)
    - 1839-1889 (Box 282)
    - No Date (A-Laf) (Box 283)
    - No Date (Lan-W) (Box 284)
  - Subseries VI.3: Supplementary Volumes
    - 1771-Sept 1781 (Box 285)
    - Oct 1781-Nov 1787 (Box 286)
    - Jan 1788-May 1790 (Box 287)
    - June 1790-Oct 1791 (Box 288)
    - Nov 1791-Aug 1793 (Box 289)
    - Sept 1793-March 1799, also 1806, 1817, 1863 & n.d. (B-U.S.) (Box 290)
  - Subseries VI.4: Special Files
    - Aide de Camp, 1778-May 1780 (Box 291)
    - General Orders, May 1799-July 1800 (Box 292)
    - Le Guen, Louis, July 1801-Jan 1826 (Box 293)
    - Military Equitation (Box 294)
    - Name and Subject File (A-W) (Box 295)
    - Society for the Establishing of Useful Manufactures (SUM), Minutes (Box 296)
  - Subseries VI.5: Treasury Department
    - Treasury, 1785-July 1793 (Box 297)
    - Treasury (plus map n.d.), Aug 1793-April 1795 (Box 298)
  - Subseries VI.6: Photocopies of Newspapers
    - Dec 1773-April 1788 (Box 299)
    - May 1788-March 1791 (Box 300)
    - April 1791-Jan 1793 (Box 301)
    - Feb 1793-Dec 1794 (Box 302)
    - 1795-1800 (Box 303)
    - 1801-1804; 1809 (Box 304)
- Series VII: Microfilms
  - Subseries VII.1: A-W
    - Adams, McHenry Simmons (Box 305)
    - Address to the Electorate of New York, 1801 (Box 305)
    - Albany Gazette, 7, 11, 21, 28 July (Box 305)
    - L'Ami des Lois, 15 Pravial an 6-22 Messidor an 6 (Box 305)
    - Aurora, 1 Jan-29 Dec 1796 (Box 305)
    - Aurora, 2 Jan-30 June 1797 (Box 305)
    - Aurora, 1 July-30 Dec 1797 (Box 305)
    - Aurora General Advertiser, 1798 (Box 305)
    - Aurora General Advertiser, 1799 (Box 305)
    - Aurora General Advertiser, 1800 (Box 305)
    - Aurora General Advertiser, 1801 (Box 305)
    - Baltimore Daily Intelligencer, Aug-Oct 1794 (Box 305)
    - Bates, W.K., Ph.D. 1951 (Box 305)
    - Blaine, Ephraim Papers, 1-4 May 1967 (Box 305)
    - Boston Gazette/Boston Independent Chronicle, June-Dec 1793 (Box 305)
    - Brymner Canadian Archives, 1890 (Box 305)
    - Burr-Hamilton Duel material, NY Historical Society (Box 305)
    - Burr, Public Conduct of, for Angerstein vs. Burr (Box 306)
    - Burr, Le Quen (Box 306)
    - Callender, James T. History of the US for 1796 (Box 306)
    - Cassanova Letterbooks, 1790-1804 (Box 306)
    - [Charleston] Carolina Gazette/[Savannah] Georgia Gazette, May-June 1802 (Box 306)
    - [Charleston] Carolina Gazette, March 1803 (Box 306)
    - Cholonen-White Letter Book (Box 306)
    - Claus Papers, Vol. 4 (Box 306)
    - Claypoole's "American Daily Advertiser", 1796 (Box 306)
    - Clemente Library-Hamilton Broadsides, 1789 (Box 306)
    - Commerical Advertiser (New York), 26 Feb 1802 (Box 306)
    - Cormere, Observations (Box 306)
    - Court Records, Georgia, 1789 (Box 306)
    - Court Records, South Carolina, 1787-1795 (Box 306)
    - Court Records and New London Custom House Records (Box 306)
    - Coxe Family Papers, Jan-June 1793 (Box 306)
    - Coxe Family Papers, July 1793-June 1795 (Box 307)
    - Coxe, Tench Papers (Box 307)
    - Coxe, Tench Papers, Aug 1795-Jan 1798 (Box 307)
    - Craig, Isaac Papers (Box 307)
    - Croswell Case/Van Ness Report (Box 307)
    - Delaware Historical Society (Box 307)
    - Duel, 1804 (Box 307)
    - Dunlap's Daily American Advertiser, June-Dec 1793 (Box 307)
    - Dunlap and Claypoole "American Daily Advertiser", Jan 1794-June 1795 (Box 307)
    - Dunlap and Claypoole "American Daily Advertiser", Jan-Dec 1795 (Box 308)
    - Elkins, Wilson H. 1794-1807 (Box 308)
    - Esterquist Dissertation, U of Chicago (Box 308)
    - The Examination, 1802 (Box 308)
    - Expenditures, Jan 1797-Dec 1802 (Box 308)
    - Federal District and Circuit Courts, 1790-1859 (Box 308)
    - Federal Gazette, 10 Oct 1791-4 April 1794 (Box 308)
    - Fish Papers: Notes for a life of Hamilton, 10 Oct 1791-4 April 1794 (Box 308)
    - Ministere des Affaires Estrangeres, Memoirs, et Documents, Etats-Unis Vols. 2, 3, 9, 10, 14, Paris (Box 308)
    - Ministere des Affaires Estrangeres, Memoirs, et Documents, Etats-Unis Vols. 15, 17, 18, 40 (pt. 1-7), 41 (pt. 1-5), 42 (pt. 1-7), Paris (Box 309)
    - Index Archives du Ministere des Affaires Estrangeres, France (Box 309)
    - Frances, Andrew Claim (Box 309)
    - French Foreign Archives: Conversation of French Ministers and Hamilton (Box 309)
    - Gazette of the United States, 3 Sept 1791-31 Dec 1794 (Box 309)
    - Gazette of the United States, 2 Jan 1795-31 Dec 1800 (Box 310)
    - General Advertiser, "Aurora", 1795 (Box 310)
    - Gerry Correspondence (Box 310)
    - Ragen, Katherine M., Ph.D. Hamilton's Economic Policy, 1936 (Box 310)
    - Hamilton: Address to the Electors of NY, 21 March 1801 (Box 310)
    - Bowdoin, G.T. Hamilton: Letters (Box 310)
    - Hamilton: Letter Concerning the Public Conduct of John Adams, Esq., Pres. (Box 310)
    - Hamilton: Letters from the Adams Papers (Box 310)
    - Hamilton: Pickering Letters (Box 310)
    - Hamilton: Miscellaneous, Historical Society of PA (Box 310)
    - Hamilton Papers, Essex Institute (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers, Livingston Collection (Box 311)
    - Hamilton and M.C. Lane Papers (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers, Honrich (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers: Miscellaneous Documents (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers: NH1 (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers: Morristown (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Papers: Peyer, Columbia (Box 311)
    - Hamilton Reports (Box 311)
    - Hampshire Gazette, Northhampton, MA (Box 311)
    - Hawkes Life of Hamilton (Box 311)
    - Hughes, Hugh Letter Books (Box 311)
    - Jefferson, Thomas Papers, 13 Nov 1792-14 May 1793 (Box 311)
    - Jefferson Papers, 15 May 1793-20 Nov 1794 (Box 312)
    - Kent, James Papers (Box 312)
    - King, Letters to Hamilton (Box 312)
    - Land, Holland Papers (Box 312)
    - Lansing, Strayer (Box 312)
    - Leonidas, A Reply to Lucius Junius Brutus (Box 312)
    - Lincoln, Benjamin Letterbook (Box 312)
    - Livingston: Surrett order, misc. (Box 312)
    - London Gazette (Box 312)
    - McHenry, James Letter (Box 312)
    - McKesson: Papers relating to NY State ratification of the Constitution (Box 312)
    - Madison: Debates (Box 312)
    - Madison, James Papers; Notes of Debates, 1782-1783 (Box 312)
    - Miranda, Venezuela (Box 312)
    - Morris, Robert Account Books, v. 1 (Box 312)
    - Morris, Robert Account Books, v. 2 (Box 313)
    - Morris, Robert Account of Property (Box 313)
    - Murray, William Vans Commonplace Book, 1795-1797 (Box 313)
    - Olney, Jeremiah Letters (Box 313)
    - National Gazette, 31 Oct 1791-26 Oct 1793 (Box 313)
    - Neville Papers (Box 313)
    - New England Papers: Inspection Trip, June 1800 (Box 313)
    - New York & Albany newspapers: Albany Register, 17 Feb, 13 March, 27 March 1801 (Box 313)
    - New York & Albany newspapers: Albany Centinel, 17, 24 April 1801 (Box 313)
    - New York & Albany newspapers: (NYC) American Citizen, 7 March 1801 (Box 313)
    - New York & Albany newspapers: (NYC) Spectator, 8 Oct 1800, 18 Feb 1801 (Box 313)
    - New York & Albany newspapers: Party Addresses: NY Gubernatorial Election, 1801 (Box 313)
    - New York Argus, July-Nov 1795 (Box 313)
    - New York Argus, 24 Dec 1795 (Box 313)
    - New York Argus, 27 May 1796-13 May 1797, 1-22 May 1798 (Box 313)
    - New York Argus, 23 May 1798-31 Dec 1798 (Box 313)
    - New York Artillery Company Pay Book: Cash Book (Box 313)
    - New York Daily Advertiser, 2 Jan 1792-7 June 1793, (3 reels, ) (Box 313)
    - New York Daily Advertiser, 8 June 1793-30 June 1795, (4 reels, ) (Box 314)
    - New York Evening Post, 16 Nov 1801-31 Dec 1804 (Box 314)
    - Rommell, John New York Evening Post, 1809-1818 (Box 314)
    - New York Gazette and General Advertiser, 14 Aug-Oct 1798 (Box 314)
    - New York Journal, May-Dec 1793 (Box 314)
    - New York Minewa, 2 May 1796-8 April 1797 (Box 314)
    - New York Minewa, 10 April 1797-30 Sept 1797 (Box 314)
    - New York Argus, 1 Dec 1795-26 May 1796 (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Miscellaneous, 1799-1800 (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Sedition Case (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Accident to C.C. Pinckney (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Riot at West Point (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Hamilton's New England Trip (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Washington Funeral (Box 314)
    - New York Papers - Yellow Fever (Box 314)
    - New York State Ratifying Convention: Melancton Smith notes (Box 314)
    - New York State Convention: Nicholas Power Journal, 17 June 1788 (Box 314)
    - Pennsylvania Gazette, Aug 1792-Dec 1793 (Box 314)
    - Pennsylvania Gazette, 1 Jan 1794-25 Feb 1795 (Box 315)
    - Pennsylvania Governor's Papers, (3 reels, ) (Box 315)
    - Pennsylvania Insurrections, (2 reels, ) (Box 315)
    - Pennsylvania Gazette, 13 Nov 1798 (Box 315)
    - Pennsylvania Gazette, 1-20 Nov 1798 (Box 315)
    - Pennsylvania Independent Gazetteer, 1, 6, 22, 25, 29 April, 10 June 1795 (Box 315)
    - Massachussets Historical Society Pickering Papers, 1, 6, 22, 25, 29 April, 10 June 1795 (Box 315)
    - Pittsburgh Gazette, 19 Jan 1793-25 Feb 1797 (Box 315)
    - Public Records Office: F.O.115: vol. 1-6:1 (Box 315)
    - Rawk Papers - Insurrection in Western PA (Box 315)
    - Merchant's Daily Advertiser "Reynold's Affair" (Box 315)
    - Richmond Examiner, 8 Dec 1801-10 Jan 1804 (Box 315)
    - Riggs, J.B. Miscellaneous Mss. (Box 315)
    - Riggs Research (Box 315)
    - Savannah City Gazette, March-April 1802 (Box 316)
    - Spectator, New York, 3 Jan 1801-14 July 1804 (Box 316)
    - Stenben's Claim (Box 316)
    - Treasury Collection, 1789-1816 (Box 316)
    - Ulster Gazette, 13 Aug 1803 (Box 316)
    - United States vs. Schooner Peggy, Court Records, Sept 1800-April 1801 (Box 316)
    - Virginia Gazette, 25 July 1792-6 May 1795 (Box 316)
    - Virginia Gazette, 13 May 1795-Dec 1796 (Box 316)
    - Virginia Gazette, Jan 1798-1 Oct 1799 (Box 316)
    - Virginia State Library, USDC (Box 316)
    - Washington Federalist, 1 Dec 1800-14 March 1801 (Box 316)
    - Washington Federalist, 22 Feb-April 1802 (Box 316)
    - Washington, George Application under (Box 316)
    - Washington, George Papers: Series 2, vol. 16-37, (6 reels, ) (Box 316)
    - Washington, George Papers: Series 4, 10 Jan 1793-28 Feb 1795, (4 reels, ) (Box 317)
    - Washington, George Papers (J.B. Riggs) (Box 317)
    - Webster, Noah Aristedes, Open Letter to Alexander Hamilton (Box 317)
    - Western Star, Stockbridge, MA (Box 317)
    - Wolcott, Oliver Loose Letters (Box 317)
    - Wolcott, Oliver Papers: vol. 26-28 (Box 317)
  - Subseries VII.2: Alexander Hamilton Documents in the National Archives
    - Revolutionary War; Post-Revolutionary War; Secretary of War's Office (Box 318)
    - Treasury Department Records (Box 318)
    - Records of the Bureau of Accounts; Records of the US Coast Guard (Box 318)
    - Records of the Bureau of Customs (Box 318)
    - "Old Loans" - Public Debt Records (Box 318)
    - Public Debt; Treasury Deptartment; Internal Revenue Service; Private Papers (Box 318)
    - State Department Records (Box 318)
    - US House Records (Box 318)
    - House of Representatives (Box 318)
    - National Historical Publications Commission (Box 318)
    - Office of the Attorney General; Office of the Postmaster General; Treasury Department Organization (Box 318)
    - General Accounting Office (Box 318)
    - Records re: Foreign Accounts, 1782-1797; State Deprtment Records (Box 318)
    - Selected Documents (Box 318)
  - Subseries VII.3: Documents from the National Archives
    - Letters from and Opinions of Attorney General, 1791-1811 (Box 318)